So
the way it's done
on our town budgets is it's on the revenue tab
as a credit against how much in taxes we have to raise,
so it offsets both RAM and
AES.
On the third commitment, is that how would you care? No, and it's
done this way for a couple different reasons. So I don't know if you remember in the past that ECS funding has been held hostage by the state multiple times over the years.
And so
if we put it in the school as a revenue item,
either school,
we would be behind
then to pay RAM,
and behind
then to pay the school,
because they'd be waiting on those dollars when the state holds them hostage.
So what we actually do is simply say, this is how much money we got to educate our children
under education cost sharing.
And also keep in mind, it literally goes up and down every year.
So by doing it this way,
the school gets their money in
lump sums. So they get a big payout
August,
and they get another large payout
>> in January. Sorry, I should have not said that.
The
only reason I'm asking is because a lot of us seem to be
thinking about the fact
that the state gave them, so that it's a lower number, and some towns report that number not including the money the state gave them. So if you go to the state of Connecticut website and you use
>> their they table
actually don't allow that. So every school has to report exactly the same way.
In fact,
the state of Connecticut did a workshop, was it two years ago, Jeff?
At Rand High School,
And we actually went to go and learn how this was done. And they,
ironically enough, Andover, because we start with an A, was on the top of his list sheet.
So he literally said, you know what, we'll just use Andover since you're here. And he literally walked us through how our numbers will affect.
And also affects,
and the reason it's equalized is because the
state also
has to take into account if you have, let's say a special education student that has a very high dollar amount. Yes. That could completely skew the number. They
pull some of these things out to offset it so that it's even across the board. Okay. Okay? So yeah, it is actually equalized by the state and they have a formula.
And I may still have that guy's information. I'll see if I can find it for you, but he was actually really,
you know, was very open to problems. Appreciate it, thank you. I'll see if I still have his card. Okay, thank you.
Okay,
>> so So
unfortunately,
well I shouldn't say unfortunately, it's actually the way our charter is
done purposely, is that
the board of selected the board of finance
does not have finite control over the school budget.
So they can't
tell you where those ones will be cut. And only the school board could do that when they make those decisions. As Chris has already pointed out, they're a little concerned about how they're gonna get there
given the amount of the cut that they've already received.
Ask even for a certain small student population?
Even with a small student population. And there is instances available where you can
have a very part time one,
but if the school board has made a decision that they feel this is the appropriate number of hours to have the person
Okay.
Good night.